### Contact

775-233-5640 (Mobile) sdaunique@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ silviadevescovi (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Healthcare Management
Hospitals
Healthcare

### Languages

Spanish (Limited Working)
English (Native or Bilingual)

### Certifications

Registered Nurse Missouri License

Former Certifications: Trauma
Nurse Specialist (TNS) ~ Certified
Emergency Nurse (CEN) ~
Advanced Cardiac Life Support
(ACLS) ~ American Heart
Association Certified First Aid & BLS
Instructor ~ NV Licensed Certified
Nursing Assistant (CNA) Instructor
Registered Nurse California License
Registered Nurse Nevada License
Inactive Registered Nurse Licenses:
Kansas ~ Illinois ~ Wisconsin ~
North Carolina

### **Publications**

"Establishing Professional Expectations"

# Silvia Devescovi, BSN, RN

Chronic Conditions Coordination | Consultant Chronic Conditions | Value-Based Population Health | Sustainable Community Greater New York City Area

## Summary

- ► Chronic Conditions Care Educator Consultant
- ► Helping you "Achieve Patient Outcomes" with a Unique Approach to Care Coordination ◄
- ► Value-Based Population Health Sustainable Community

I provide educational support with healthcare teams through Care Coordination education for Wellness & Chronic Care Conditions

As a Chronic Conditions Care Educator for the healthcare team, I teach & demonstrate effective, organized patient centered activities between inter-professionals.

Using my expertise, & keen insight, I address ambivalence for behavior change, which is demonstrated, implemented & evaluated for success, thereby minimizing Chronic Conditions Care complications.

I effectively manage project assignments through provider & hospital relations. Reviewing medical records; as well as coordinating care with clients to identify Quality Indicators, including Quality Measurement strategies & evidence-based quality measurement results in a variety of databases.

- ►► SPECIALTIES ◄◄
- Motivational Interview (MI) Health Coaching ~ Electronic Communications & In-person
- Expanding Chronic Care Conditions Nursing Process
- Manage Care Transitions for better Patient Outcomes & Cost Savings

- Physician Relations as Partners
- ► To learn how I may help you find a reduction in costs & maximize cost savings through Value-Based Care: defined as patient outcomes divided by total cost per patient. As well as, to brainstorm & collaborate on any of these perspectives, please call me at 775-233-5640. ◄

\*

Recruiters, HR Managers, Hiring Managers connect with me to get access to my network deep in industry leadership.

| Resume available upon request |

Connect with me:

►► sdaunique@yahoo.com ◄◄

## Experience

Chronic Conditions Care | Educator | Value-Based Population Health | Sustainable Community

Chronic Conditions Care | Care Coordination | Educator | Consultant September 2006 - Present (13 years 11 months)

Astoria New York Area ~ Accepting a permanent position

Registered Nurse, RN • Chronic Conditions Care • Care Coordination •
 Educator • Healthcare Consultant • Value-Based • Population Health

People share with me, that I have a strong ability to utilize my acquired professional nursing skills, with patients, in person, as well as through electronic communications, so to empower them, to self-manage, and prevent further complications of their Medical Chronic Condition(s). Accomplished through an educational base of information, motivation and behavioral choices; resulting in a healthier person and sustainable community.

I coordinate and collaborate with "your" care-based team, so to provide health services and establish effective partnerships with patients, caregivers, and their physicians. Using a shared and achievable goal-model, within and across

all healthcare continuum, there by creating an excellence of measurable quality of care with patients, families and physicians, which is at the center.

Through optimizing network management, I am able to facilitate the appropriate delivery of healthcare services and effective referrals, while creating a value-based cost driven result.

Attend Networking Events about Care Coordination, Chronic Conditions Care Support

Research Industry Leaders who are Care Coordinators, specializing in Chronic Conditions Care

Track Industry Trends in Chronic Conditions Care and Quality Management

Participate in Industry Discussions about Value-Based and Population Health

Collaborate with Healthcare Professionals specializing in Value-Based, Chronic Conditions Care

Top 5 Chronic Conditions Care

- Cardiac
- Pulmonary
- Diabetes
- Depression
- Arthritis/Chronic Pain Management

StrengthFinder Top 5 STRENGTHS

- » Unifier Connectedness
- » Potential Cultivator Maximizer
- » Believer Responsibility
- » Personalizer Relator

#### » Motivator - Strategic

Healthcare Management | Healthcare Education Chronic Conditions Care | Care Coordination | Educator | Consultant May 1980 - May 2020 (40 years 1 month)

Lived in Missouri, Kansas, California, Nevada, Illinois & presently Astoria, NY

Registered Nurse since 1981

I am a dedicated Registered Nurse, Educator and Nurse Management professional with a 36-years proven track record of providing quality, patient-oriented care in a variety of environments including Government, HMO, Profit/Non-Profit and University Hospitals.

My unique strategies in overseeing NCQA, URAC & Joint Commission assessments which base results of clinical performance and consumer experience that applies to all types of health plans, as well as hospital & clinical practice groups; drives cost savings with improved quality measures resulting in savings for healthcare providers.

Former Certifications: Trauma Nurse Specialist (TNS) ~ Certified Emergency Nurse (CEN) ~ Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS) ~ American Heart Association Certified First Aid and BLS Instructor ~ Nevada Licensed Certified Nursing Assistant (CNA) Instructor

Optum (formerly Alere Wellbeing)

Chronic Conditions Care Educator - Care Coordination - Electronic Communications

September 2006 - March 2013 (6 years 7 months)

My proficient approach in completing electronic communications health assessments with members through health coaching, delivers educational support and offer emotional support; with the potential to improve patient care and assist clinicians struggling with insufficient time. Engaged the member by guiding the health coaching process and identifying the member's own personal motivation to change unhealthy behaviors. I provided self-management support while bridging the gap between clinician and member. I helped close the care gaps by showing members how to navigate the health care system.

Using my expertise I developed and implemented well-defined goal-based plans and monitored members through specific and measurable objectives

including device monitoring, which the member is able to attain. And, established a collaborative working relationship to create an individualized and prompt reward. Coached participants about critical signs, causes and consequences of condition implications and promote effective health behaviors that include support and resources, as well as participant safety.

Communicated with member's healthcare providers, when indicated, to enhance and update member's treatment plans. Input clinical data thoroughly, correctly and in a timely manner. Always keeping in mind the company standards and confidentially while following HIPPA guidelines.

# Education

Avila University
Bachelor's Degree, Nursing Science · (1976 - 1980)